# **EROS CASAS**

# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Forward-thinking Web Programmer and Software Engineer able to adapt to new concepts when developing applications, forms, and databases. Fluent in Java, Python, HTML, Javascript, and Flask. Learn new languages and refine methods already learned in the past experiences.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Arts, Computer Science, 06/2020

Luther College - Decorah, IA

## **WORK HISTORY**

#### Hardware Software Technician, 10/2016 to 12/2019

Luther College, Decorah, Iowa

- Solving software and hardware problems involving both faculty and students
- Replaced hardware components within complex computer builds and identified any damage the computer was at risk of
- Ensured to carefully follow procedures to extracted user's data from hardware and to prevent data corruption
- Explained technological terms in a way non-tech users will easily understand
- Deployed software to Luther College workstation remotely and in-person
- Created and added in documentation to the Help desk and Hardware procedures

#### Internship Student, 01/2018 to 01/2018

Whole Foods, Chicago, IL

- Communicated effectively with management and instructors and openly accepted critiques and suggestions for areas of improvement.
- Maintained and updated all project related documents.
- Under supervisor, learned Angular, Typescript, and React methods to use in a dynamic website environment.

## **Support Technician**, 05/2017 to 08/2017

Luther College, Decorah, IL

• Spend time on assisting and receiving feedback in improving the

Address: Chicago, IL 60608

**Phone:** (312) 219-0113

**Email:** ecasas182015@gmail.com

https://casaer01.github.io /ErosCasasResumeWebsite/

# PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- Linux Environment
- · GitHub and Git efficient
- HTML
- JavaScript
- Angular and React
- Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- C++
- Docker
- Testing and maintenance
- Communication
- Project Management
- Java knowledge
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- TypeScript
- Database Management
- SQL
- Agile
- Hardware and software installation

Luther College software.

- Gave feedback on ways to improve the Luther's Ticketing system.
- Worked in other departments outside the Technology Help Desk when workers were needed such as the software department.
- Spent time re imaging Luther College computer for the upcoming semester.
- Configured hardware, devices and software to set up work stations for Luther employees.
- Troubleshot and diagnosed problems to accurately resolve wide range of technical issues.

### **Assistant**, 06/2014 to 08/2014

Chicago Public Schools, Chicago, IL

- Researched public school information.
- Assisted in organizing events, filing important papers, and proper destruction of confidential papers.
- Managed office inventory by restocking supplies and placing purchase orders to maintain adequate stock levels.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

## **Microsoft Office Specialist**

Excel 2010, Powerpoint 2010, Word 2010

#### **Learning Docker**

• Issued Jul 2020

#### Learning React.js

Issued Jan 2020